<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Hopefully Helpful]]></title>
  <link href="http://kristjan.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kristjan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-29T06:23:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kristjan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kristján]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing environment between machines]]></title>
    <link href="http://kristjan.github.com/blog/2012/06/30/sharing-environment-between-machines/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-30T12:49:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kristjan.github.com/blog/2012/06/30/sharing-environment-between-machines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To facilitate setup of new machines, I keep configuration on GitHub at
<a href="https://github.com/kristjan/.dotfiles">kristjan/.dotfiles</a> and
<a href="https://github.com/kristjan/.vim">kristjan/.vim</a>. This way, all I have to do to
set up my environment is install Git and clone those repos. <code>.dotfiles</code> comes
with an install script that just symlinks each dotfile from <code>~/.dotfiles/$FILE</code>
to <code>~/$FILE</code>.</p>

<p>A problem, though, is that some tools&mdash;like things that talk to
GitHub&mdash;need a private token or other data to exist somewhere in my
configuration. I can&#8217;t go putting those in a public repo, so until now I&#8217;ve had
to either look them up or copy them from an old machine. This time, the old
machine is my old laptop sitting at home and available via SSH thanks to Back to
my Mac. Rather than remember the ID BTMM assigns me as part of its lengthy
hostname, I have another environment variable that also doesn&#8217;t belong in a
repo. These things were sitting in my configs where I had to <code>git patch</code> around
them and ran the risk of at some point accidentally pushing them out.</p>

<p>The solution I&#8217;ve landed on is to store these in Dropbox and load them before
the rest of my configs and helpers. The top of my <code>.bashrc</code> looks like this:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>HELPERS="
</span><span class='line'>  Dropbox/.env
</span><span class='line'>  .aliases
</span><span class='line'>  .functions
</span><span class='line'>  .nvm/nvm.sh
</span><span class='line'>"
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>for helper in $HELPERS; do
</span><span class='line'>  if [ -f $HOME/$helper ]; then
</span><span class='line'>    . $HOME/$helper
</span><span class='line'>  fi
</span><span class='line'>done</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>And <code>Dropbox/.env</code> contains:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>export GITHUB_TOKEN=&lt;token&gt;
</span><span class='line'>export BOBBLE_HOST=bobble.&lt;id&gt;.members.btmm.icloud.com</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Now my configs are public and easy to trade with people (which I do regularly to
learn new tricks), but private or irrelevant data is safely where only I can see
it (assuming the integrity of Dropbox). During setup, I just install Dropbox
before I clone my dotfiles, and everything is slightly more magical.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Disassociate Your Google Account From Someone Else's]]></title>
    <link href="http://kristjan.github.com/blog/2012/03/12/how-to-disassociate-your-google-account-from-someone-elses/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T23:33:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kristjan.github.com/blog/2012/03/12/how-to-disassociate-your-google-account-from-someone-elses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I frequently get emailed new account information by people who are some subset
of [confused, foreign, children] and believe that my email address is their
email address. What I didn’t realize, or perhaps noticed but promptly forgot, is
that 10 solid people had used my GMail address as the backup address when they
created their Google account. This is the address to which you can send a
password reset should you ever lose access to your main account.</p>

<p>There is a rather large security flaw in this system, though granted one only
brought on by user error: None of these 10 accounts were verified by me as being
validly attached to their primary account. That is, when the confused user
listed my address as secondary, I either did not receive a confirmation email
before the two could be linked, or I certainly ignored it. The result is that
by virtue of a simple typo, a stranger can get full access to your GMail
account, and by extension probably everything you do online.</p>

<p>Not only that, but you can find out which accounts list yours as the secondary,
so even in the absence of verification notifications, a complete set of
exploitable accounts is readily available.</p>

<p>Happily for these 10 hapless internet users, I was not in a playful/evil mood
when I discovered this, so I spent the past 15 minutes severing the connections.
Which, by the way, is somewhat roundabout unless I missed a page.</p>

<ol>
<li>Enter your email address at
<a href="https://www.google.com/accounts/ForgotPasswd?service=mail&amp;fuOnly=1">https://www.google.com/accounts/ForgotPasswd?service=mail&amp;fuOnly=1</a></li>
<li>For each address sent to you, request a password reset from
<a href="https://www.gmail.com">GMail</a>, or some other Google login</li>
<li>At the bottom of each password reset email is a link to disavow the account</li>
</ol>


<p>I also sent these folks a nice email describing what had happened and
recommending that they be more careful in the future. I only hope they speak
English / read it properly, because otherwise I’m sure to get a good set of
interesting, upset replies.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
